[
  {
    "Question": "Several users (transactions) can access locked data at the same time in display mode. A request for another lock is accepted even if it comes from another user. What type of lock is being referred to here?",
    "opt1": "Exclusive (write lock)",
    "opt2": "Exclusive, but not cumulative lock (enhanced write lock)",
    "opt3": "SAP lock",
    "opt4": "Shared lock (read lock)",
    "correctAns": "Shared lock (read lock)",
    "resource": "https://help.sap.com/viewer/8e6d3c3875b84ccf80e3bbf939a2b59e/1909.000/en-US/d073b9a4bfc34759b47820795b1d846e.html",
    "proposedAns": ""
  },
  {
    "Question": "What will happen if the lock object is not used for database update?",
    "opt1": "Database table will not be updated",
    "opt2": "It may lead to inconsistency as someone else might be updating the record at the same time",
    "opt3": "Tables will be updated with the warning message",
    "opt4": "Explicit commit is required as SAP stores the value internally but does not update the database table unless commit is executed",
    "correctAns": "It may lead to inconsistency as someone else might be updating the record at the same time",
    "resource": "https://help.sap.com/viewer/8e6d3c3875b84ccf80e3bbf939a2b59e/1909.000/en-US/ce19366a16f2451c8a5127d4b91cd015.html",
    "proposedAns": ""
  },
  {
    "Question": "The database system releases each database lock if an implicit database commit is triggered.",
    "opt1": "Application server (AS) ABAP.",
    "opt2": "True",
    "opt3": "False",
    "correctAns": "True",
    "resource": "https://help.sap.com/viewer/8e6d3c3875b84ccf80e3bbf939a2b59e/1909.000/en-US/ce19366a16f2451c8a5127d4b91cd015.html",
    "proposedAns": ""
  },
  {
    "Question": "Is a special table-related function module that is created automatically when you activate a table-related lock object.",
    "opt1": "Lock Module",
    "opt2": "Commit Module",
    "opt3": "Enqueue Module",
    "opt4": "Dequeue Module",
    "correctAns": "Lock Module",
    "resource": "https://help.sap.com/viewer/8e6d3c3875b84ccf80e3bbf939a2b59e/1909.000/en-US/ce19366a16f2451c8a5127d4b91cd015.html",
    "proposedAns": ""
  },
  {
    "Question": "Why are the dequeue modules hardly used?",
    "opt1": "Locks are released automatically at the end of the program",
    "opt2": "Locks are passed over to update techniques",
    "opt3": "Locks are only used in certain situations",
    "opt4": "None of the above",
    "correctAns": "Locks are released automatically at the end of the program",
    "resource": "https://help.sap.com/viewer/8e6d3c3875b84ccf80e3bbf939a2b59e/1909.000/en-US/ce19366a16f2451c8a5127d4b91cd015.html",
    "proposedAns": ""
  },
  {
    "Question": "All database locks are released no later than the next database commit or rollback.",
    "opt1": "True",
    "opt2": "False",
    "correctAns": "True",
    "resource": "https://help.sap.com/viewer/8e6d3c3875b84ccf80e3bbf939a2b59e/1909.000/en-US/ce19366a16f2451c8a5127d4b91cd015.html",
    "proposedAns": ""
  },
  {
    "Question": "ENQUEUE and DEQUEUE modules are generated by default when lock objects are activated.",
    "opt1": "True",
    "opt2": "False",
    "correctAns": "True",
    "resource": "https://help.sap.com/viewer/8e6d3c3875b84ccf80e3bbf939a2b59e/1909.000/en-US/ce19366a16f2451c8a5127d4b91cd015.html",
    "proposedAns": ""
  },
  {
    "Question": "The following are true about database locking.",
    "opt1": "Database systems set physical locks on all lines affected by a database call.",
    "opt2": "Read locks prevent the setting of further read locks for the objects in question.",
    "opt3": "Read locks prevent other transactions from setting write locks for the objects in question.",
    "opt4": "Write locks allow other transactions to set read locks for the objects in question.",
    "correctAns": [
      "Database systems set physical locks on all lines affected by a database call.",
      "Read locks prevent other transactions from setting write locks for the objects in question."
    ],
    "resource": "https://help.sap.com/viewer/8e6d3c3875b84ccf80e3bbf939a2b59e/1909.000/en-US/ce19366a16f2451c8a5127d4b91cd015.html",
    "proposedAns": ""
  },
  {
    "Question": "If an application program that has created lock entries is terminated, the system releases the locks automatically(implicitly).",
    "opt1": "True",
    "opt2": "False",
    "correctAns": "True",
    "resource": "https://help.sap.com/viewer/8e6d3c3875b84ccf80e3bbf939a2b59e/1909.000/en-US/ce19366a16f2451c8a5127d4b91cd015.html",
    "proposedAns": ""
  },
  {
    "Question": "You can send the contents of the lock container to the lock management by using the “ENQUEUE_ESFLIGHT” function module.",
    "opt1": "True",
    "opt2": "False",
    "correctAns": "True",
    "resource": "https://help.sap.com/viewer/8e6d3c3875b84ccf80e3bbf939a2b59e/1909.000/en-US/ce19366a16f2451c8a5127d4b91cd015.html",
    "proposedAns": ""
  },
  {
    "Question": "Mode _______ sets a lock for changing data and can be accumulated.",
    "opt1": "A",
    "opt2": "B",
    "opt3": "C",
    "opt4": "E",
    "correctAns": "E",
    "resource": "https://help.sap.com/viewer/8e6d3c3875b84ccf80e3bbf939a2b59e/1909.000/en-US/ce19366a16f2451c8a5127d4b91cd015.html",
    "proposedAns": ""
  },
  {
    "Question": "The existing enqueue and dequeue function module scan be used for optimistic locks.",
    "opt1": "True",
    "opt2": "False",
    "correctAns": "False",
    "resource": "https://help.sap.com/viewer/8e6d3c3875b84ccf80e3bbf939a2b59e/1909.000/en-US/ce19366a16f2451c8a5127d4b91cd015.html",
    "proposedAns": ""
  },
  {
    "Question": "The optimistic lock is converted into an exclusive lock (type 'e') by using lock mode.",
    "opt1": "A",
    "opt2": "E",
    "opt3": "R",
    "correctAns": "E",
    "resource": "https://help.sap.com/viewer/8e6d3c3875b84ccf80e3bbf939a2b59e/1909.000/en-US/ce19366a16f2451c8a5127d4b91cd015.html",
    "proposedAns": ""
  },
  {
    "Question": "A pessimistic lock is set if the user displays data in the change mode.",
    "opt1": "True",
    "opt2": "False",
    "correctAns": "True",
    "resource": "https://help.sap.com/viewer/8e6d3c3875b84ccf80e3bbf939a2b59e/1909.000/en-US/ce19366a16f2451c8a5127d4b91cd015.html",
    "proposedAns": ""
  },
  {
    "Question": "Lock object is created with the initial letter.",
    "opt1": "R",
    "opt2": "D",
    "opt3": "C",
    "opt4": "E",
    "correctAns": "E",
    "resource": "https://help.sap.com/viewer/8e6d3c3875b84ccf80e3bbf939a2b59e/1909.000/en-US/ce19366a16f2451c8a5127d4b91cd015.html",
    "proposedAns": ""
  },
    {
      "Question": "SAP locks are dependent on database locks?",
      "opt1": "Yes",
      "opt2": "No",
      "correctAns": "Yes",
      "resource": "https://help.sap.com/viewer/8e6d3c3875b84ccf80e3bbf939a2b59e/1909.000/en-US/d073b9a4bfc34759b47820795b1d846e.html",
      "proposedAns": ""
    },
    {
      "Question": "Can we create more than one lock objects for a table?",
      "opt1": "Yes",
      "opt2": "No",
      "correctAns": "Yes",
      "resource": "https://help.sap.com/viewer/8e6d3c3875b84ccf80e3bbf939a2b59e/1909.000/en-US/d073b9a4bfc34759b47820795b1d846e.html",
      "proposedAns": ""
    },
    {
      "Question": "Shared lock cannot be created on the entry that does not exist in database table?",
      "opt1": "Yes",
      "opt2": "No",
      "correctAns": "Yes",
      "resource": "https://help.sap.com/viewer/8e6d3c3875b84ccf80e3bbf939a2b59e/1909.000/en-US/d073b9a4bfc34759b47820795b1d846e.html",
      "proposedAns": ""
    },
    {
      "Question": "Can a lock object be made RFC enabled?",
      "opt1": "Yes",
      "opt2": "No",
      "correctAns": "Yes",
      "resource": "https://help.sap.com/viewer/8e6d3c3875b84ccf80e3bbf939a2b59e/1909.000/en-US/d073b9a4bfc34759b47820795b1d846e.html",
      "proposedAns": ""
    },
    {
      "Question": "All the locks in SAP are managed by ‘Enqueue Server’.",
      "opt1": "True",
      "opt2": "False",
      "correctAns": "True",
      "resource": "https://help.sap.com/viewer/8e6d3c3875b84ccf80e3bbf939a2b59e/1909.000/en-US/d073b9a4bfc34759b47820795b1d846e.html",
      "proposedAns": ""
    },
    {
      "Question": "Naming convention for lock object is",
      "opt1": "Z_NAME",
      "opt2": "D_NAME",
      "opt3": "EZ_NAME OR EY_NAME",
      "correctAns": "EZ_NAME OR EY_NAME",
      "resource": "https://help.sap.com/viewer/8e6d3c3875b84ccf80e3bbf939a2b59e/1909.000/en-US/d073b9a4bfc34759b47820795b1d846e.html",
      "proposedAns": ""
    },
    {
      "Question": "What table fields are required as lock argument in a lock object?",
      "opt1": "Any primary key fields and any secondary key fields",
      "opt2": "The foreign key dependencies",
      "opt3": "The primary key fields",
      "opt4": "Any primary key fields",
      "correctAns": "The primary key fields",
      "resource": "https://help.sap.com/viewer/8e6d3c3875b84ccf80e3bbf939a2b59e/1909.000/en-US/d073b9a4bfc34759b47820795b1d846e.html",
      "proposedAns": ""
    },
    {
      "Question": "Which transaction is used to view lock table?",
      "opt1": "SM11",
      "opt2": "SM37",
      "opt3": "SM12",
      "correctAns": "SM12",
      "resource": "https://help.sap.com/viewer/8e6d3c3875b84ccf80e3bbf939a2b59e/1909.000/en-US/d073b9a4bfc34759b47820795b1d846e.html",
      "proposedAns": ""
    },
    {
      "Question": "Lock table is stored in ‘Lock Server’ / ‘Enqueue Server’?",
      "opt1": "Yes",
      "opt2": "No",
      "correctAns": "Yes",
      "resource": "https://help.sap.com/viewer/8e6d3c3875b84ccf80e3bbf939a2b59e/1909.000/en-US/d073b9a4bfc34759b47820795b1d846e.html",
      "proposedAns": ""
    },
    {
      "Question": "We have created a lock object ‘EZ22_EKKO’. Then name of generated FM will be?",
      "opt1": "Enqueue_ez22_ekko and dequeue_ez22_ekko",
      "opt2": "ez22_ekko_ Enqueue and ez22_ekko_ dequeue",
      "opt3": "FM will not be generated",
      "correctAns": "Enqueue_ez22_ekko and dequeue_ez22_ekko",
      "resource": "https://help.sap.com/viewer/8e6d3c3875b84ccf80e3bbf939a2b59e/1909.000/en-US/d073b9a4bfc34759b47820795b1d846e.html",
      "proposedAns": ""
    },
    {
      "Question": "If a table is locked in Exclusive mode, another user request for read lock. What will happen?",
      "opt1": "Lock will be granted in display mode",
      "opt2": "Lock will not be granted",
      "correctAns": "Lock will not be granted",
      "resource": "https://help.sap.com/viewer/8e6d3c3875b84ccf80e3bbf939a2b59e/1909.000/en-US/d073b9a4bfc34759b47820795b1d846e.html",
      "proposedAns": ""
    },
    {
      "Question": "User had locked a table for the key1 = ‘45000012’ in exclusive mode. Another exclusive lock request comes from different user for key1 = ‘45000013’. What will happen?",
      "opt1": "It will not allow to lock the table as table has been locked in E mode",
      "opt2": "Lock will be granted",
      "correctAns": "Lock will be granted",
      "resource": "https://help.sap.com/viewer/8e6d3c3875b84ccf80e3bbf939a2b59e/1909.000/en-US/d073b9a4bfc34759b47820795b1d846e.html",
      "proposedAns": ""
    },
    {
      "Question": "User had locked a table for the key1 = ‘ABCD’ in shared mode. Another shared lock request comes from different user for same key. What will happen?",
      "opt1": "Lock will not be granted",
      "opt2": "Lock will be granted",
      "correctAns": "Lock will be granted",
      "resource": "https://help.sap.com/viewer/8e6d3c3875b84ccf80e3bbf939a2b59e/1909.000/en-US/d073b9a4bfc34759b47820795b1d846e.html",
      "proposedAns": ""
    },
    {
      "Question": "Which of the following statement is correct?",
      "opt1": "Without call of FM ‘DEQUEUE_LOCK_OBJECT_NAME’, lock can never be released from the table.",
      "opt2": "After the end of transaction, lock released automatically",
      "correctAns": "After the end of transaction, lock released automatically",
      "resource": "https://help.sap.com/viewer/8e6d3c3875b84ccf80e3bbf939a2b59e/1909.000/en-US/d073b9a4bfc34759b47820795b1d846e.html",
      "proposedAns": ""
    },
    {
      "Question": "If we set parameter ‘_wait’ value as ‘X’ in FM ‘ENQUEUE_LOCK_OBJECT_NAME’. What will happen?",
      "opt1": "Foreign lock exception will be triggered as soon as lock request is rejected",
      "opt2": "Lock request will be repeated at the set of intervals until the system time limit.",
      "opt3": "Lock request will be repeated until it acquires the lock",
      "correctAns": "Lock request will be repeated until it acquires the lock",
      "resource": "https://help.sap.com/viewer/8e6d3c3875b84ccf80e3bbf939a2b59e/1909.000/en-US/d073b9a4bfc34759b47820795b1d846e.html",
      "proposedAns": ""
    },
        {
          "Question": "If we set parameter ‘_COLLECT’ as ‘X’ in FM ‘ENQUEUE_LOCK_OBJECT_NAME’. What will happen?",
          "opt1": "System places lock requests or release requests in a local lock container",
          "opt2": "System sends lock requests or release request directly to the lock server",
          "correctAns": "System places lock requests or release requests in a local lock container",
          "resource": "https://help.sap.com/viewer/8e6d3c3875b84ccf80e3bbf939a2b59e/1909.000/en-US/d073b9a4bfc34759b47820795b1d846e.html",
          "proposedAns": ""
        },
        {
          "Question": "‘_SCOPE’ parameter in FM ‘ENQUEUE_LOCK_OBJECT_NAME’ has default value",
          "opt1": "3",
          "opt2": "2",
          "opt3": "1",
          "correctAns": "3",
          "resource": "https://help.sap.com/viewer/8e6d3c3875b84ccf80e3bbf939a2b59e/1909.000/en-US/d073b9a4bfc34759b47820795b1d846e.html",
          "proposedAns": ""
        },
        {
          "Question": "Which parameter returns username if foreign lock exception occurs in ‘Enqueue’ function module?",
          "opt1": "SY-MSGV3",
          "opt2": "SY-MSGV2",
          "opt3": "SY-MSGV1",
          "correctAns": "SY-MSGV1",
          "resource": "https://help.sap.com/viewer/8e6d3c3875b84ccf80e3bbf939a2b59e/1909.000/en-US/d073b9a4bfc34759b47820795b1d846e.html",
          "proposedAns": ""
        },
        {
          "Question": "Which mode of locking can be requested more than one time by same transaction?",
          "opt1": "E and X",
          "opt2": "X and S",
          "opt3": "E and S",
          "correctAns": "E and S",
          "resource": "https://help.sap.com/viewer/8e6d3c3875b84ccf80e3bbf939a2b59e/1909.000/en-US/d073b9a4bfc34759b47820795b1d846e.html",
          "proposedAns": ""
        },
        {
          "Question": "Can we pass wildcard character ‘@’ in our lock argument?",
          "opt1": "Yes",
          "opt2": "No",
          "correctAns": "Yes",
          "resource": "https://help.sap.com/viewer/8e6d3c3875b84ccf80e3bbf939a2b59e/1909.000/en-US/d073b9a4bfc34759b47820795b1d846e.html",
          "proposedAns": ""
        },
        {
          "Question": "TCODE for defining locks?",
          "opt1": "SE12",
          "opt2": "SE11",
          "opt3": "SE13",
          "correctAns": "SE12",
          "resource": "https://help.sap.com/viewer/8e6d3c3875b84ccf80e3bbf939a2b59e/1909.000/en-US/d073b9a4bfc34759b47820795b1d846e.html",
          "proposedAns": ""
        },
        {
          "Question": "The following are true about database locking: Database systems set physical locks on all lines affected by a database call. Read locks prevent the setting of further read locks for the objects in question. Read locks prevent other transactions from setting write locks for the objects in question. Write locks allow other transactions to set read locks for the objects in question. Which statement is correct?",
          "opt1": "All are correct",
          "opt2": "Read locks prevent further write locks from being set",
          "opt3": "Write locks prevent further read locks from being set",
          "correctAns": "All are correct",
          "resource": "https://help.sap.com/viewer/8e6d3c3875b84ccf80e3bbf939a2b59e/1909.000/en-US/d073b9a4bfc34759b47820795b1d846e.html",
          "proposedAns": ""
        }
      ]
      
  
